Fredo St Fleur

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack web developer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 1+ year of experience, including mentoring 3+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. Strong skills include React, Database management, PostgreSQL, and Ruby.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

November 2022 - September 2023

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 40+ full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming.

<u>Vacay Inn</u> — It offers a user-friendly interface to explore and book accommodations, access exclusive deals, and discover local attractions, making trip planning both useful and fun for travelers.

- Developed user interface with React Native, and architected a backend server using Ruby on Rails.
- Implemented user authorization and authentication using BCrypt and JWT.
- Actively participated in code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members, fostering a collaborative development environment.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills and adaptability in overcoming technical challenges throughout the project.
- Built with: (React | Rails | RoR | PostgreSQL) See Source.

<u>Food App</u> — Whether you're a foodie or just looking for a quick bite, this app makes food exploration both useful and enjoyable for everyone.

- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams to ensure the project met all functional and design requirements.
- Effectively communicated project updates and requirements with team members and stakeholders, ensuring everyone was aligned on project goals and progress.
- Contributed to the maintenance and optimization of the codebase, ensuring long-term scalability and performance.
- Contributed to the maintenance and optimization of the codebase, ensuring long-term scalability and performance.
- Built with: (Ruby | RoR | PostgreSQL | Bootstrap) See Source.

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

May 2023 - July 2023

- Mentored 3+ junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews using Slack or Zoom.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance by 90%.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain 3+ students longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

November 2022 – September 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

HAITI TEC

December 2019 - December 2021

IT Computer, Full Time

Awards and honors: Stood up among the top 50 students in the country.